Edward Fenno Hoffman III Papers
Edward Fenno Hoffman III Papers
1952-1964
Hoffman, Edward Fenno, 1916-
0.25 linear ft.
American sculptor. Collection includes printed material, clippings, correspondence, photographs and other material.
2741983
Biographical History
Edward Fenno Hoffman III (1916-1991) was an American sculptor known for his portraits, children, and religious themes. He studied at the Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts and worked with Paul Manship briefly. For three years (1952-1955) he was Sculptor in Residence at the Henry Clews Memorial Art Foundation in France, and hs first New York exhibition was in 1956. He was recognized by numerous societies, including a "Best in Show" from the National Sculpture Society (1961), and his work is in the permanent collections of many notable musuems.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Edward Fenno Hoffman III Papers consists of artwork, biographical material, correspondence, and memorabilia.
Artwork consists of reproductions of Hoffman's work -- mostly photographs but there is also one printed item.
Biographical material contains a brief autobiographical summary, including education, awards, and shows. The latest date given is 1964.
Correspondence is entirely incoming. Correspondents include family ("Auntie Grace"), art world benefactors such as Archer Milton Huntington and Marie Elsie (Mrs. Henry) Clews, and fellow sculptors Henry Rosin, Donald De Lue, EvAngelos "Angelo" Frudakis, and Walter Hancock.
Memorabilia contains clippings about Hoffman, exhibit catalogs, and a brief essay on him by Claude Saulnier.
Arrangement of the Collection
Alphabetically by topic or title. Correspondence is arranged chronologically.
Related Material
has numerous collections relating to American sculptors. Please to locate additional material.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Sculptors; Clews, Marie, 1880-1959.; De Lue, Donald, 1897-1988.; Frudakis, EvAngelos.; Hoffman, Edward Fenno, 1916-; Huntington, Archer M. (Archer Milton), 1870-1955.; Rosin, Harry.; Saulnier, Claude.; Art, American -- 20th century.; Sculptors -- United States.; Sculpture, American -- 20th century.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Essays.; Exhibition catalogs.; Photographs.; Artists.; Sculptors.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Edward Fenno Hoffman III, 1971, 1988.
Inventory
- Artwork reproductions
  - Photographs, photos of Hoffman's sculpture (Box 1)
  - Printed items, 1964; brochure showing a medal designed by Hoffman for Southern Baptists Convention (Box 1)
- Biographical material
  - Biographical sketch by Hoffman, 1964 (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - General, 1930; 1948-1952 (Box 1)
  - General, undated; includes one about Hoffman, giving the writer's thoughts about him (Box 1)
- Memorabilia
  - Clippings, 1950-1962; 1988,; undated (Box 1)
  - Exhibit catalogs and notices, 1956; 1961,; 1964-1965,; 1970,; undated (Box 1)
  - "Some comments about the American artist, Ned Hoffman" by Claude Saulnier, undated; carbon typescript, printed brochure with excerpt (Box 1)